As we think through your marketing channels,
我在讲营销媒介渠道的时候 你会经常听到我
you'll likely hear me referring to a channel that is either paid, earned, or owned.
提到这些术语：付费媒体 (paid)；赢得媒体（earned）；自有媒体（owned）
Now, these are fairly common terms used in the day-to-day of marketing.
这些是日常营销里经常用到的术语
So let's take a minute to make sure we're on the same page.
所以 我会花点时间向你解释下这些概念 确保我们的理解是一致的
Your paid media will make up everything that you, well, pay for.
顾名思义 付费媒体就是付费使用的媒体媒介
This includes channels like newspaper ads,
包括报纸、
radio spots, Facebook ads, and direct mailing.
广播、Facebook、邮寄广告等
Your owned media is everything that includes your website,
自有媒体包括你的网站、
your list of customers that you use to send out your emails,
顾客邮寄名单、
or even a blog that has an active readership.
拥有一定活跃度的博客等
Earned media is the world of organic press.
赢得媒体是指企业没花钱就得到的媒介
Word-of-mouth marketing, mentions on other blogs,
比如 口碑、社交媒体、博客推荐、
and news articles written about you all make up channels within earned media.
新闻报道等 都属于赢得媒体
Now, you might be asking yourself,
好了 问题来了
"What about social media?"
“社交媒体属于哪一类？”
Well, social media actually can live within all three.
社交媒体实际上可以属于所有的这三种类别
Social media could be a channel that you buy ads on paid,
比如 你可以在社交媒体上购买付费广告
it could be a channel by which you own the property and send messages out,
你也可以在社交媒体上建立官方账号 营销自己的品牌
or it could be an area by which you're earning mentions on
你也可以在社交媒体里获得其他人的推荐
other people's social handles such as someone posting a tweet about you.
比如 有忠实用户发了关于你的品牌的推文
Now, all of these channels will overlap,
事实上 这三种媒介是有重合的地方的
just as they overlap with social media.
就像社交媒体不单属于某一类
These make up the foundation of marketing.
这些就是营销媒体渠道的基本部分
Let's talk about owned media.
我们先来说说自有媒体
I think it's really easy to start here because this is really primarily your own website.
自有媒体比较容易开始 主要就是你的官方网站
Here, you're tracking how many visitors,
你可以追踪网站的访客量
where they're coming from,
点击来源
what pages they're visiting,
页面浏览情况
how long they've stayed,
页面停留时间
and even what page they left from.
甚至在哪个页面离开的
When you look at your owned analytics,
通过对自有媒体的分析
you get a sense of how users are finding your site,
你可以知道用户都是怎样发现你的网站的
if they found what they want,
你的网站是否满足了他们的需求
if you're advertising objectives or driving a meaningful amount of traffic,
你的广告营销是否能产生一定的流量？
and even whether your product or service is meeting the goals of your customers.
你的产品或者服务是否满足了客户的需求
With a resource like Google Analytics,
你也可以用 Google Analytics
you install a tracking code and from there,
安装追踪代码
you have that goldmine of data to leverage segment and correlate.
就可以有大量的数据可以分析了
For example, let's say you make a change to your website and you
比如 你对网站做出了某种改动
notice on that day web traffic drops dramatically.
然后你发现在改动的当天 网站流量掉得很厉害
Well, now you have a sense of where to start looking for that problem.
那么你就知道问题大概出在哪里了
If you rolled out a new landing page,
再比如 如果你对网站首页进行了改版
you might see an increase in conversions resulting from that specific page,
你可能会看到首页的转化率提高了
or perhaps you see a sudden spike in traffic.
或者流量突然增加了
By drilling into that,
再深入研究 你可能会发现这些数据变化的来源
you can identify the source such as a social media post or a mention on an online blog.
可能是社交媒体或者博客上的一篇推荐推文
Now, let's take a look at paid data.
现在 我们来讲付费媒体
When you run online paid advertisements,
如果你选择线上付费广告
you'll find that the platform you use is typically tied to several reports.
你可能会发现付费广告平台通常都会使用一些固定的报告
This data is extremely useful as it can give you
这些报告极其有用 它们会告诉你
granular details on which ads are working,
很多细节 比如哪些广告是有效果的
what targeting makes sense, and more.
如何投放才是合理的 等等
If you're paying for ads in print or sponsorship within your local community,
如果你是通过纸媒或者当地媒体的赞助方式
you might have to leverage unique ways to capture data.
那可能就要想一些另外的办法 来收集数据
This could involve a landing page with a custom URL or even accustomed phone number.
比如 通过特定的 URL 或者 手机号码 可以链接到特定首页
Oftentimes, you'll have to attach records from various sources in
通常 我们需要查看不同来源的报告
order to understand what's happening with those particular campaigns.
来评估某个广告营销的表现
If you run a promotion,
如果你在做一个促销活动
you might, for example,
你可能会需要追踪
keep track of the amount of coupons that come through the door.
优惠券的使用情况
Now, it's harder when you move into broadcast media to really measure the impact.
当你使用广播媒体的时候 就比较难评估它的效果
For that, you often have to really start to correlate trends and changes.
这个时候 你就需要全局地看各种趋势和数据变化
Oftentimes, it's better to work with the agency that's running
通常会比较建议和代理机构来合作电视或者广播广告投放
your TV or radio spots to really get into the nitty gritty of analyzing that data.
他们会提供所需的数据来进行分析
Now, the final part comes from earned media.
最后一个是赢得媒体
This one is typically the most difficult.
这个通常是最难的
Here, your outcomes aren't necessarily determined by
对于赢得媒体 效果的衡量不是看花了多少钱
spend but how interesting people think your product and services are.
而是看你的产品和服务的口碑
Here, you're tracking things like your social media fanbase,
赢得媒体的指标可以是 社交媒体的粉丝数量
how many mentions you have in articles or your share of voice.
媒体曝光率 话语权等
You may have many dashboards that you collect this data in and you'll want to
有很多面板可以提供相关数据 除了传统广告指标以外
look at it alongside all of your other advertising metrics.
赢得媒体的指标也要重视起来
The best way to measure results with earned media is to have
衡量赢得媒体表现的最佳方式是
your own goals and objectives that you are comparing that data to.
设定可以进行数据比较的目标
So for example, you decide that a mention in
比如 在杂志上被提及一次
a magazine would increase your revenue potential by a $1,000.
将会贡献 1000 美元的收入
Well, now you can track how you're trending
有了量化指标 你就可以更好的评估
towards that goal and the effort you're investing.
你的进度以及你投入的成本
Remember, we're always trying to layer this data towards that objective,
记住 我们应该在目标里考虑到切实的数据
so we remember what metrics we need to get us there.
这样才能确认通过实现哪些指标 可以最终实现目标
Now, there's an endless amount of data providers out there as we saw,
市面上有无数的数据供应商
so investigate them against your needs and keep a system
所以你应该根据自己的需要来选择
in place that provides you with the necessary checks and balances.
最好有自己的使用体系 才能互相核实数据